Jacob Werner

Cedar Rapids, IA 1229 - 251 - 9512

jswerner2011@gmail.com ✓

linkedin.com/in/jakeswerner in

Summary

Accomplished Leader, able to take charge and direct staff in stressful situations while maintaining composure. Effective communicator, skilled in working effectively with people across all organizational levels in courteous and professional manner. Ability to analyze, learn, and implement complex rules and regulations while making prompt decisions.

Skills

- Problem Solving
- Report Writing
- Team Oriented

- Communication
- Ethically Grounded
- Experienced Leader

Experience

JANUARY 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

Line Service Technician / Signature Flight Support, Cedar Rapids, IA

In charge of providing on the ground support for private jets and general aviation, ensuring outstanding customer service and fast service. A variety of services including, marshalling, fueling, hangar storage, towing, and coordination for taxiing aircraft on the ramp. Provides commercial fuel service for multiple airlines.

JANUARY 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

Inventory Specialist-Truck Lead / Best Buy, Coralville, IA

Leads a team of 5 people within tight deadlines to complete inventory receiving and stocking. Handles all outbound and inbound shipping on a daily basis while preserving an accurate receipt of goods. Assists employees and customers in locating and purchasing various products.

JULY 2015 - APRIL 2018

Fire Team Leader / United States Air Force, Moody AFB, GA

Lead three ground combat specialists, ensuring each assigned squad was proficient with skills and maintained equipment. Conducted written annual evaluations of Airmen for career and personal growth. Instructed team members on weapon systems and technology for security and base defense.

Fire Team Member / United States Air Force, Moody AFB, GA

First responder to detect and halt security threats; trained for crisis/emergency situations. Conduct interviews and write reports for various incidents including; damaged vehicles, lost/stolen resources, surveillance and security. Maintain qualifications on weapon systems and ready to deploy overseas within 72 hours.

Education

PRESENT (MAY 2021)

BA in Ethics and Public Policy / University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA

FEBRUARY 2018

AS Criminal Justice / Community College of the Air Force, Montgomery, AL

JANUARY 2018

Weapon Station (CROWS) Instructor Course / 820th Base Defense Group, Moody AFB, GA

JULY 2017

Airman Leadership Course / Air Force Education and Training, Moody AFB, GA

Volunteer Experience

MAY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2016

President / Ghost Walker Association, Moody AFB, GA

A non-profit private organization set up to support the families of active duty military members of the 824th Base Defense Squadron. While deployed or at home; sets up family events, fundraisers, separation gifts, and donates to those in need. Donated and supported the building of a memorial for fallen soldiers at Moody Air Force Base.